# Sai Surya Kalagani

ksaisurya304@gmail.com ,416-829 6734 , https://<u>www.linkedin.com/in/surya185</u> , https://saisurya.netlify.app/ Toronto , Ontario

Accomplished web developer with over four years of comprehensive experience in designing, developing, and optimizing web applications and websites. Expert in leveraging JavaScript technologies including React.js and Node.js, with a deep proficiency in the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js). Demonstrated success in agile project management, leading to significant improvements in system performance and user engagement.

**SKILLS** 

**Front-end:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, EJS, React, Next JS, Vue.js, PHP, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, EJS, Webflow, TypeScript, GraphQL, Responsive Web Design, UI/UX Design

**Back-end:** Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB,MYSQL, REST API, AJAX, Amazon Web Services (AWS) - S3 & CloudFront, Authentication and Authorization (OAuth, JWT)

Other skills: Agile Development Methodologies (Scrum), Version Control Systems (Git), Testing and Debugging (Jest), DevOps and Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VideoForm - Full Stack Developer (Hyderabad, India)

**MAY 2021 - DEC 2022** 

- Developed JavaScript-based web applications using Node.js, Express.js, React.js, and MongoDB.
- Increased customer acquisition by 50% through the implementation of user-friendly features using Tailwind CSS,
  JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, and MongoDB.
- Reduced internal server errors by 40% through the addition of various validations, enhanced user interaction, and improved code structure.
- Designed and developed an Analytics Panel that facilitated client onboarding.
- Integrated the extension with over 100+ CRM platforms, significantly reducing integration process time.
- Created a JavaScript Chat Bot widget, embeddable in any website, enabling clients to receive personalized video feedback.

#### GreyMetrics - Front-End Web Developer ( Hyderabad , India )

**JAN 2019 -DEC 2020** 

- Developed 25+ integrations for data retrieval and automated reporting in a JavaScript-based web application using Node.js, Express.js, Angular.js, and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with the Marketingand Development teams to define product requirements and roadmap.
- Built the user-facing web application using Angular 4 for the front-end and Node.js for the backend.
- Configured application releases into test and production environments.

### Aquo Digital - Front-End Web Developer ( Hyderabad , India)

**AUG 2018 - JAN 2019** 

- Led development, testing, and deployment of a dynamic e-commerce website (<u>vijayadiagnostic</u>) with an intuitive admin panel for client content management
- Collaborated with three clients to understand their vision and incorporate feedback into the development process, ensuring client satisfaction
- Created a 50-page website for driver training courses (<u>dubaidrivingcenter</u>)
- Implemented security measures to protect sensitive medical patient data using MongoDB and AWS S3
- Integrated a secure payment gateway for online transactions

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Post Graduate Diploma- Web Development (Brantford, Ontario)

APR 2023 - AUG 2019

Conestoga College

Bachelor's in computer science (Hyderabad, INDIA)

AUG 2014 - MAY 2018

B V Raju institute of Technology.